ブリタニアの少年 ルルーシュは
謎の少女から特殊な力を手に入れた
Lelouch, a Britannian youth, has been
given special powers by a mysterious girl.
“ギアス”
Geass.
いかなる相手にでも命令を下せる
絶対遵守の力
The absolute power to command
anyone to do anything.
ルルーシュは この“ギアス”を武器に
ブリタニア帝国の破壊を決意する
Lelouch is determined to use this
power of Geass as a weapon...
to destroy the Britannian Empire.
母の仇を討ち
In order to avenge his mother...
妹ナナリーが幸せに過ごせる
世界を作る為に
as well as to create a world in which his
younger sister Nunnally can be happy.
その先に待つのは
父 ブリタニア皇帝だと知りながら
At the end of his quest he knows his own father,
the Britannian emperor, awaits him.
少なくとも それが当時のルルーシュの
願いであった
Or at least,
that was what Lelouch hoped for.
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
Jibun wo sekai sae mo
The moment when I might be able...
Kaete shimae sou na shunkan wa
To change myself and even the world
瞬間は 何時も直ぐ傍に…
Itsumo sugu soba ni
It's always right there at my side
Kakusenu iradachi to
Even as I stood still, looking at myself
隠せぬ苛立ちと
立ち尽くす自分を 見つめ
Tachitsukusu jibun wo mitsume
With undisguised frustration
迷いながら 悩みながら
Mayoi nagara nayami nagara
Feeling lost, feeling anguished
悔やみながら 決めればいいさ
Kuyami nagara kimereba ii sa
Feeling mournful, deciding what to do
君がくれた 言葉ひとつ
Kimi ga kureta kotoba hitotsu
All it took was a single word from you
戸惑いは消え去り
Tomadoi wa kiesari
And my uncertainty vanished
Karappo datta boku no heya ni hikari ga sashita
You let the light shine into what was my empty room
からっぽだった 僕の部屋に 光が射した
Miageta oozora ga
The sky I had been looking up at...
見上げた大空が 青く澄み切って行く
Aoku sumikitte yuku
Cleared and turned blue
閉ざした 窓を 開く事を決めた
Tozashita madowo hiraku
And I decided to throw open...
Koto kimeta
The windows that were kept closed
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
Jibun wo sekai sae mo
The moment when I might be able...
Kaete shimae sou na shunkan wa
To change myself and even the world
瞬間を 感じる今ここに…
Kanjiru ima koko ni
I feel it right here with me
HIS NAME IS ZERO
この銃 なんだか分かるな？
Do you know anything about
this weapon, Suzaku Kururugi?
枢木スザク
クロヴィス殿下殺害に使われた物だ
線条痕も確認済み
It was the one used to
assassinate Prince Clovis.
The barrel striations confirm this.
それと 調べさせてもらったよ
I also took the liberty of investigating.
君は日本最後の総理大臣
その嫡子だそうだなぁ
You're the son of Japan's last
prime minister, aren't you?
動機も十分
You had plenty of motive!
何かの間違いです
You've made some sort of mistake!
自分はこんな銃 見た事もありません
I've never seen that gun in my life!
うっ
くっ…
君の指紋が検出されているんだよ
Your fingerprints showed up on it.
君には親衛隊の殺害容疑もかかっている
You're also suspected of murdering
members of the royal guard.
認めたまえ
Admit it.
今ならイレヴンではなく
Do it now and you'll be judged as an
honorary Britannian instead of as an Eleven.
名誉ブリタニア人として
裁いてもらえるぞ？
自分は… やっていない！
I didn't do it!
うっ！
ねぇ スザクさんですよね？
さっきのニュース
That was Suzaku they mentioned
before on the news, wasn't it?
ああ スザク 生きてたんだな
Yeah. It looks like Suzaku's still alive.
うん 戦争のあと
お別れしちゃったままでしたから
Yeah.
We've been apart since the war ended.
私達だって…
Even we...
お兄様？
Big brother?
なんだい？
What?
嘘ですよね ニュース…
That news wasn't true, was it?
嘘だよ
It wasn't.
あのスザクがそんな事するはずがない
Suzaku would never do anything like that.
It's some kind of mistake.
何かの間違いだよ
そう… ですよね
Yes... It must be.
ああ
Right. So...
だから
おやすみ ナナリー
Good night, Nunnally.
だから さっさと声明を出せば
よかったんだ！
That's why we should've
issued a statement sooner!
俺達の手柄になったのによー
We could've claimed credit for it!
はぁ ナオト…
Naoto...
やっぱり俺には無理だよ
リーダーなんて
I'm just not cut out for this.
I'm no leader.
ああ 全て注文通りのはずだ
Ah, everything should be
as you requested.
こっちの世界では
超一流って奴がやってるし
It's being worked on by the
finest person in the field.
スライドシステムも確認済み
The slide system is also being confirmed.
あとは証拠を全て消して
私が忘れてしまえば いいんだよな？
Once I erase all the evidence,
I should forget all about this, correct?
誠に痛ましい事件でした
This was truly a painful incident.
このエリア11の総督であり
We have lost our beloved and respected
Prince Clovis, viceroy of Area 11.
敬愛すべきクロヴィス殿下は
既におられません
しかし 私達はこの悲しみに
耐えねば ならないのです
However, we must bear this sadness!
それを力とせねばならないのです
We must take strength from it!
うーん もう
肝心なパーツが 無くなっちゃって
We've lost our most essential part.
なんとか ならないんですか？
Can't we make do without him?
そうなんだよ よそのパイロットは
所属がガチガチで動かせないし
I wish.
We can't get a replacement
pilot for love or money,
頼めたとしても 彼並みの数値は
出せないだろうし
and even if we could,
they wouldn't get readings like he did.
言ったっけ？　通常稼働率94％
代わりのパーツと言ったって…
Didn't I tell you? He had an operation
efficiency of 94%! How do we replace that?
だから スザク君を釈放する為に
Then you should tell them
that so they'll release Suzaku!
彼 名誉ブリタニア人だろ？
He's an honorary Britannian, right?
バトレー将軍の失脚以降
軍は純血派が抑えてるからねぇ
Since Gen. Bartley's disgrace, the Purebloods
have been in control of the military.
純血派って？
Purebloods?
ブリタニア軍は ブリタニア人だけで
構成するべきだって連中だよ
They say that only pureblood Britannians
should serve in the Britannian military.
彼らからすれば ブリタニア軍人から
とがびとを出す訳にはいかない
According to them, the guilty party
can't be from the Britannian military.
でも 犯人がイレヴンなら
ジェレミア辺境伯が言うように
But if the criminal is an Eleven,
they'll accept Margrave Jeremiah's demands...
エリア11の名誉ブリタニア人制度を
廃止する きっかけになる
and shut down the entire system of granting
Elevens the status of honorary Britannian.
じゃぁ スザク君は…
And what about Suzaku?
無罪って事は ないだろうね
I doubt there's any way
he'll be found innocent.
あ…
ルッ ルーシュ！　このあと どうする？
Lelouch, what are you up to later?
せっかく授業が なくなったんだし
前から頼まれてた これ
We shouldn't waste
a day off from classes,
and people have been
asking for a rematch...
ダメよ 賭け事はっ！
Don't you dare go gambling!
堅い事 言うなってぇ
Gimme a break!
そうだな もうやめるよ
She's right. I'm through with that.
えっ！
Huh?!
もっと手ごわいのを見つけた
I've found a better opponent.
はい？
What? What do you mean?
何よ それ？
だったら 俺にも かませろって！
Then let me in on it, too!
うっははは
やめた方がいいって
そういうのじゃないし
You'd better not.
It's not your sort of game.
ブリタニア軍の圧倒的な勝利は
もうまいな 旧日本政府に対し
The overwhelming
victory of Britannia...
made the unenlightened
former government of Japan...
その序列を自覚させました
well aware of their
true rank in the world.
以降 帝国とイレヴンは手を取り合い
復興への道を歩み始めたのです
Since then, the empire and
Eleven have joined hands...
and have begun to walk
the road towards revival.
16時に東京タワー
よりによって こんな所に
Tokyo Tower, 16:00 hours.
Why here, of all places?
連絡してきたのは枢木スザクだろ？
It was Suzaku Kururugi
who contacted us, right?
断定はするな
Don't jump to conclusions.
しかし カレンに電話した後で
捕まったのかも…
But he might have been
arrested after he called Kallen.
だとしたら ここは危険過ぎる
Then this place is too dangerous for us to stay.
アッシュフォード学園からお越しの
カレン・シュタットフェルト様
Miss Kallen Stadtfeld of Ashford Academy,
a lost item has been turned in for you.
落とし物が届いております
展望フロア サービスカウンターまで
お越し下さい
Please come to the service counter
on the observation deck floor.
繰り返しお客様にお伝えします
I repeat, for the following visitor...
こちらで間違いないでしょうか？
You're sure this is yours?
あの… お客様のですよね？
It's yours, isn't it?
えっ ええ ありがとうございます
Y-Yes! Thank you so much.
本当だよなあ…
It's so true! Things turned out
so well, thanks to Prince Clovis.
クロヴィス殿下のおかげで
うまくいってた
ブリタニアから援助してもらったから…
Thanks to Britannia,
we've been able to rebuild so quickly!
ん！
ゼロ？
Zero?
はい もしもし
Yes? Hello?
環状５号線 外回りに乗れ
お友達も一緒だ
Ride the outer tracks of loop line #5.
Bring your friends.
えっ？
殿下の追悼番組 よくできていたよ
少し泣かせが過ぎるようだが…
His Highness's memorial program
was handled very well.
A bit too weepy for my tastes, but...
閣下 大衆は涙を望んでおります
Your Excellency, the masses enjoy a tearjerker.
テレビ屋らしい発想だなぁ
Spoken like a true TV man.
Still, I acknowledge your skills.
しかし手腕は認めよう
あれだけの時間でよくも…
You did well in the short time you had.
まるで殿下の死を
あらかじめ知っていたようじゃないか
One would almost think you were
expecting His Highness to die.
恐れながら 重要な人物の追悼番組は
常に用意しております
I'm afraid it's quite common to have memorial
programs prepared for important people.
私のも あるのか？
For me as well?
今回の事で閣下もリストに
上がるかもしれません
After this, we may make
one for you, Your Excellency.
これまではランク外だったという訳か
正直だな
Meaning I wasn't important
enough to rate one until now.
How honest of you!
お 恐れ入ります
I'm afraid so.
軍に入る気はないか？
報道担当が手薄だ
Feel like joining the army?
We have a need for information officers.
力足らずは承知しております
私ごときでは…
I have to admit that I'm not
up to that job. It's not for me.
民放の方が好みか？
まあいい もう一仕事 頼みたい
You prefer a civilian network?
No matter. I have another favor to ask of you.
明日の夜
枢木スザクを軍事法廷へ移送する
Tomorrow night, Suzaku Kururugi
will be transferred to his court martial.
沿道に愛国的ブリタニア人を
誘導しましょう
Let's get a lot of patriotic
Britannians to line the roadside.
話が早くて助かるよ
護送は顔が よく見えるようにな
It's helpful that
you catch on so quickly.
Be sure his face can be
seen clearly in the convoy.
ジェレミア卿 イレヴンの中には
枢木一等兵を英雄視する者も居ます
Lord Jeremiah, there are
some among the Elevens...
who have made Pvt. Kururugi
out to be a hero.
奪還を考えるグループもあるかと…
Some groups may even
be thinking of freeing him.
護衛には私 自らサザーランドで出る
I'll be providing security
personally in my Sutherland.
ノコノコ出てくるようなら
その場で処刑してくれる
If any troublemakers show up,
I'll execute them on the spot!
お客様にお願い致します
Attention all passengers.
車内にて不審物があった場合
すぐにお近くのインターフォンにて
If you see a suspicious item aboard this train,
please report it at once via the nearest intercom.
もしもし
Hello?
ん！
進行方向に向かって右を見ろ
何が見える？
Face forward and look to your right.
What do you see?
ブリタニア人の街だ
The Britannians' city.
あたし達の犠牲の上に成り立つ強盗の街
A stolen city, built on our sacrifices.
では 左は？
Now look left.
あたし達の街だ
I see our city.
ブリタニアに吸い上げられた
絞りかすの街
The city made by Britannia squeezing us dry.
いい答えだ
Good answer.
では 先頭車両に来い！
All right, come to the forward car.
ん！
んん
次の停車駅はオオクボ オオクボです
ライン中央 総武
Next station: Okubo. Okubo.
Change there for the Chuo Soubu line.
Next station: Okubo.
次の停車駅はオオクボです
ライン中央 総武をご利用のお客様は
Those wishing to use
the Chuo Soubu line...
次の駅にてお乗換え下さい
あっ！
お前… なのか？
Was it you?
罠じゃ… ないよな？
This isn't a trap, is it?
なぁ シンジュクのあれは
Tell us! Was it you in Shinjuku?
Was the cease-fire order your doing, too?
停戦命令もお前なのか？
おい なんとか言えよ
Hey! Say something!
おっ
どうだ 租界ツアーの感想は
Well? What were your impressions
of this tour of the settlement?
ツアー？
Tour?
おい こんな ふざけた奴だったのか？
Hey, it couldn't
have been this joker!
正しい認識をしてもらいたかった
租界とゲットー
I wanted you to have
a true appreciation of them.
Of the settlement and the ghetto!
確かに我々とブリタニアの間には
差がある 絶望的な差だ
Yes, there's a difference
between us and the Britannians!
A desperate difference!
だから レジスタンスとしてっ
That's why we fight as the resistance!
違うな
You're wrong.
テロでは ブリタニアは倒せないぞ
Terrorism will not defeat Britannia!
倒す？
Defeat?
テロなど 子供っぽい嫌がらせに
過ぎない
Terrorism is merely
a childish nuisance.
なんだと？
What was that?!
俺達がガキだってぇのか？
Are you saying we're just kids?!
相手を間違えるな
敵はブリタニア人ではない
Don't mistake your enemy. It isn't the
Britannian people, but Britannia itself!
ブリタニアだ！
あ…
やるなら戦争だ　民間人を巻き込むな
What you need to fight is a war!
Without involving the civilians!
覚悟を決めろ！　正義を行え！
Make up your minds!
Take the path of righteousness!
ふっ ふざけるな
Don't be absurd!
It's easy to say whatever you want!
口だけなら なんとでも言える
顔も見せられないような奴の言う事が
信じられるか！
As if we could trust someone
who won't even show us his face!
そうだ！
She's right!
仮面を取れ！
Take off the mask!
なぁ 顔を見せてくれないか？
Yeah. Will you show us
your face or not?
分かった 見せよう
Very well. I'll show you.
う…
ただし 見せるのは顔ではない…
力だ！
However, what I'll show you won't
be my face, but rather my power!
不可能を可能にしてみせれば
少しは信じられるだろう
If I show you that the
impossible is possible,
you'll trust me a little, won't you?
ブリタニアの皇子を仕留めた
枢木スザクを英雄として扱わねば…
He killed the Britannian prince!
Suzaku Kururugi
should be treated as a hero!
しかし名誉ブリタニア人だぞ
But he's an honorary Britannian!
枢木総理の忘れ形見ではないか
Isn't he the son of the
late Prime Minister Kururugi?
日本を捨てた男
民衆はその存在すら知らなかった
The man who gave up Japan!
The people don't know that about him!
シンジュクの事件は
紅月達のグループだったな
The Shinjuku incident was the
work of Kouzuki's group, wasn't it?
はい 今は扇という男が継いでおります
Yes, General.
They're currently led by a man named Ohgi.
うーん 枢木の本家は
何か言ってきているか？
Has Kururugi's family said anything?
いいえ 軍籍に入ってからは
切れているようです
No, sir. They broke contact with
him after he joined the military.
どう思う？　藤堂
Your thoughts, Tohdoh?
公開処刑に付き合ってやる義理は
ないでしょう
We have no duty to join him
in a public execution.
うーん
弱気だなぁ 奇跡の藤堂ともあろう者が
Such cowardice! Are you really
Tohdoh the miracle worker?
奇跡と無謀を履き違える気はない
You shouldn't confuse
a miracle with foolishness!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
はっ…
君に頼まれていた２人
遺体リストには なかったよ
Those two you asked me about
weren't on the casualty list.
そうですか
I see.
でも 君の方は不利だなぁ
But you're not having
much luck on your end.
裁判になっても君の味方は
だぁれもいない
You may be getting a trial,
but nobody's on your side.
しかし 法廷は真実を
明らかにする場所です
But trials are where
the truth is made clear!
明かされない事の方が多いと思うけどね
真実なんてものは
I think there'll be more
obscuring going on there.
There's a precious lack of truth...
それが世界だというなら自分は
未練はありません
If you tell me that's just
how the world works...
Then... I don't regret leaving it!
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
まもなくです
Any moment. Any moment now!
まもなく時間となります
ご覧下さい 沿道を埋め尽くした
この人だかりを！
Just look at the crowds
lining the route.
皆 待っているのです
All of them, waiting! Waiting for the
man accused of killing Prince Clovis!
クロヴィス殿下殺害の容疑者
名誉ブリタニア人の
枢木スザクが通るのを！
Waiting for honorary Britannian
Suzaku Kururugi to pass by!
元イレヴンを 今か今かと
待ちかまえているのです！
Waiting for the former Eleven!
５番のカメラ遅いぞ
Camera 5's slow. Charles?
Have you got your crowd set up?
チャールズ 団体の配置は終わったか？
あぁ？　スタジオ？　待たせておけ
押してなんかいない 全て予定通り
Huh? The studio? Let 'em wait.
There's no delay.
Everything's going as planned.
来たか
Here he comes...
おっ 見えてきました　枢木容疑者です
I... I can see it!
It's Kururugi, the suspect!
枢木スザクがまもなく こちらに
Suzaku Kururugi will be here soon!
ほ～らな
There, you see?
ふん こんな 出来レース…
俺も堕ちたものだ
This sham...
I'm as corrupt as any of them.
人でなし！
Murderer! Scum! Damned Eleven!
We want our prince back!
恩知らず！
イレヴンめ！
畜生！
クロヴィス殿下を返せ！
この人殺し！
But we know that Suzaku's innocent.
スザク君は無実だって…
私達は知っているのに
法廷が僕らの証言を取り上げないって
決めたんだ 仕方ないよ
The court deemed our testimony inadmissible.
It can't be helped.
でも…
But...
Say, would that be altruism
or humanitarianism?
ねぇ それって博愛主義？　人道主義？
こんな時に言葉遊びですか？
You're playing word games
at a time like this?!
他にやる事ある？
Is there anything else I can do?
君だって知ってるでしょ
こういうケース
You know where this case
is headed as well as I do.
サミットで あの人とも連絡取れないし
もう諦めるしかないよ
And we can't contact our
patron while he's at the summit.
All we can do
is let this whole thing go.
怨嗟の声が…
怒りの声があがっています
Voices of resentment!
Voices of anger, growing louder!
殿下がどれほど愛されていたかという
証の声です
Voices giving proof of the love
the prince's people had for him!
テロリストを裁く正義の声なのです
Righteous voices
which judge the terrorist!
スザクさん！
Suzaku!
Margrave Jeremiah, whose personal
efforts helped to settle this case,
事件解決に尽力した
ジェレミア辺境伯 自らが
代理執政官として指揮をとっています
will be directing the trial
as acting consul.
できる訳ないだろ たった３人で
There's no way just the
three of them can do this!
だが 彼は言ったんだ
不可能を可能にしてみせると
But still, he told us.
That he could make the impossible possible.
あの男…
He told us he'd do it.
That he'd save Suzaku Kururugi!
枢木スザクを救ってみせると！
That's right. I don't need
a path to fall back upon.
そうだ 引き返すべき道は… いらない
ジェレミア代理執政官
Acting Consul Jeremiah!
どうした？
What is it?
Vehicle approaching the main
highway from Third Street.
サードストリートから本線に向かう
車両があります
指示通りノーチェックとしましたが
We let it pass as instructed, but...
対象はテロリストの物だと思うか？
Do you think your target
is a terrorist vehicle?
それが…
クロヴィス殿下の御料車でして…
Well, sir... It's Prince Clovis's car.
殿下の？
The prince's?!
ふざけた奴だな
構わん そのまま こっちに通せ
This guy's a joker. Never mind.
Let him through to us!
全軍停止！
All forces, halt!
えっ？
止まった　ホントに？
They stopped! They really did!
Heh! It's a coincidence!
へっ たまたまだって
でも ジェレミアの行動は
自己顕示欲の強さを示してるって…
But he said Jeremiah would do that because
he likes being the center of attention...
たまたまっ
COINCIDENCE!
ここで停止する というのは
予定にありません
No stop was scheduled here.
何かのアクシデントでしょうか？
Could there have been
some sort of accident?
こちら第５地点です
そちらに向かう車があります
This is site 5!
There's a vehicle approaching them!
ふっ
こっ これは
クロヴィス殿下専用の御料車です
It... It's Prince Clovis's
personal transport!
見えますか…
- Can you see it? It's headed towards you!
- Impossible! He's coming straight at them! What's he planning?
バカなっ 真っ正面から
どうするつもりなんだ あいつ
Will they really buy this fake?
本当に こんな張りぼてで…
I see. Just you two.
そうか お前達だけか
I'm sorry, but can you
give us a little more time?
すまない もう少し時間をくれないか？
ちゃんと話せば他のみんなも…
If I explain more,
I can get more people...
いや ２人も居れば十分だ
No. The two of you will do just fine.
なっ
バカ言うな 相手が何人いると
思ってるんだ？
Don't be ridiculous!
Do you know how many we'll be facing?!
お前達が協力してくれるなら
条件はクリアしたも同然だ
With your help, I'll clear the
conditions of this task easily.
明日までに これを作れ
外側だけ そう見えればいい
Have this made by tomorrow.
It just has to look
like this on the outside.
うっ う…
出て来い！
Get out, you who dare
to spoil His Highness' transport!
殿下の御料車を汚す不届き者が！
ん？
おぉ！
I am... Zero!
私は
ゼロ
ゼロ？
Zero?
なっ 何者でしょう この人物は？
Wh- Who is this person?!
This man calling himself Zero
who stands in front of the convoy!
自らをゼロと名乗り
護送車の前に立ちはだかっています
なんだよ これ？
What is all this?!
あ…
あいつ どうするつもりだ？
What's he doing?!
あ…
はっ はぁ…
ゼロと名乗る人物は
何者なのでしょうか？
Who is this man calling himself Zero?!
ゼロ…
Zero? As in nothing?
無という事か？
Could he be a terrorist?
テロリストなのでしょうか？
しかし だとすればあまりに
愚かな行為です
But if he is,
what a foolish move to make!
イレヴン なのか？
Is it an Eleven?
スザク 借りは返すぞ
Suzaku...
Now to return the favor.
Had enough, Zero?
Your little show is at an end!
もういいだろう ゼロ
君のショータイムは おしまいだ
はぁ くっ！
さあ まずは その仮面を
外してもらおうか
Now, first you can
remove that mask.
What the!
何？
ジェレミア卿 あれは！
Lord Jeremiah, that's!
Yes, Jeremiah.
そうだよ ジェレミア
As you never saw what was in this thing,
you assume this is a poison gas capsule.
中身を見ていない お前にとっては
こいつは毒ガスのカプセル
No! That's just...
違う それは…
ぐわぁっ
なんだ あれ？
テレビの前の皆さん
見えますでしょうか？
Can all of you watching TV now see this?
なんらかの機械と思われますが
目的は不明です
It's some sort of device,
although its purpose is unclear.
Let's keep watching and see if
this assumed terrorist explains.
テロリストと思われる人物の声明を
待ちますので しばらくお待ち下さい
こっ こいつめ
You... You bastard...
He's taken every Britannian here hostage!
ここにいるブリタニア市民を
丸ごと人質に取った
Without them even knowing
they're hostages!
それも 人質に気づかせないまま
うっ…
撃ってみるか？
分かるはずだ お前なら
You'll shoot me?
I think you know what'll happen if you try.
６班 音をひろえ
Unit 6, bring up the sound!
And get the camera in closer! Right in his face!
カメラも もっと寄るんだ 直接
But sir, this is dangerous!
でっ でもヤバいですよ なんだか
チッ アマチュアめ
Amateur!
Very well. Your demands?
分かった 要求は？
交換だ こいつと枢木スザクを
An exchange.
This for Suzaku Kururugi.
笑止 この男は
クロヴィス殿下を殺めた大逆の徒
Absurd!
This man is charged
with high treason...
for the murder of Prince Clovis!
I can't hand him over!
引き渡せる訳がない
違うな 間違っているぞジェレミア
No, you're mistaken, Jeremiah.
犯人はそいつじゃぁない
He isn't the murderer.
はっ
クロヴィスを殺したのは
The man who killed Clovis... was me!
この私だ！
嘘…
What?! It can't be! Seriously?!
あいつが？
ホントかよ…
ほぉ
まさか
I don't believe it!
The real killer!
真犯人だね
Wh-What can this mean?!
なっ なんという事でしょう
ゼロと名乗る仮面の男が…
This masked man called Zero...
No, we can't be sure it's a man.
いや 性別は分かりませんが…
ともかく自ら
But in any case,
he claims to be the real culprit!
自ら真犯人を名乗って出ました
So, where does this leave
the currently imprisoned Pvt. Kururugi?!
では 今 捕まっている枢木一等兵は
どうなるのでしょう？
やり過ぎだ 逃げられない！
He's gone too far!
We can't escape!
無理だよ もう
It's hopeless now!
イレヴン１匹で尊いブリタニア人の命が
大勢 救えるんだ
For a single Eleven, you'll save
the lives of many precious Britannians.
悪くない取引だと思うがな
I don't think it's such
a bad deal for you.
こいつ 事件をショーにするつもりか？
He's playing this whole
thing like it's a show!
こやつは狂っている
He's mad, I tell you!
殿下の御料車を偽装し愚弄した罪
あがなうがいい！
Disguising this truck as His Highness's,
He mocks us! We'll make him pay!
Are you sure about this?
You want the public to know about Orange?
いいのか？　公表するぞ オレンジを
ん？
なんだ オレンジって？
What's Orange?
さあ？
I don't know.
私が死んだら公開される事になっている
そうされたくなければ…
If I die, it'll all go public.
If you don't want that to happen...
なんの事だ？　何を言っている？
What are you talking about?
What are you saying?!
私達を全力で見逃せ そっちの男もだ！
Let us go with all your might.
That man you hold as well!
Hmpf! Understood!
ふんっ 分かった その男をくれてやれ
Give them the prisoner!
へっ？
ジェレミア卿 今なんと？
Lord Jeremiah,
what did you just say?!
その男をくれてやれ！
Give them the prisoner!
はぁ？
Should we?
いいのか？
But...
しかし…
Let them have him! Nobody will interfere!
くれてやれ！　誰も手を出すな
どういうつもりだ そんな計画は…
What are you thinking,
making a deal like this?!
キューエル卿
Lord Kewell! This is an order!
これは命令だ
I can't tell from here what happened,
ここからだと何があったのか
分かりませんが
枢木スザクの拘束が解かれるようです
but it looks like Suzaku Kururugi's
release has been arranged!
そいつは犯罪者よ 何をやっているの？
おい
Who the hell?
君はいったい？
うっ
I didn't expect
they'd allow you to speak.
やはり 声をあげる事は
できないようだな
えいっ ここで逃がしたら私達は…
If they get away, we'll be disgraced!
Zero, it's time.
ゼロ 時間だ
では 話はあとで
Then we'll talk later.
うわー
キャー
卑怯なイレヴンめっ ふっ！
You cowardly Elevens!
Lord Jeremiah, why?!
ジェレミア卿 どうして？
I told you not to interfere!
言ったはずだ 手を出すなと
飛び降りた？　やはり仲間が
They jumped?!
They must have accomplices!
It worked! Now we can...
やった これで…
うっ…
Fools! You thought you'd
escape from amidst our guards?!
愚か者め！　警備網の ど真ん中で
キューエル卿
Lord Kewell!
はっ
Will you follow my orders or not?!
私の命令に従えないのか？
これ以上の行為は処罰の対象となる
Any further actions will result in punishment!
いいな 全部隊に徹底させろ
Is this clear?! I'll say this to all units!
全力をあげて奴らを見逃すんだ
Let them go with all your might!
I really didn't think he'd save him.
まさか本当に助け出すなんて
なんなんだ あいつは？
Who is this guy?
バカバカしい あんな はったりが
何度も通用するかってぇの
It's bull! How many times
can a bluff like that work?!
しかし認めざるを得ない
But there's something
you have to admit.
え？
Huh?
彼以外の誰に こんな事ができる？
Who else but he
could have pulled that off?
Even the Japan Liberation Front
couldn't do this.
日本解放戦線だって無理だ
少なくとも僕にはできない
Or at least, I can't do it.
みんなが無理だと思っていた
ブリタニアとの戦争だって
We all thought that war with
the Britannians was impossible.
うっ…
やるかもしれない 彼なら
But maybe, with him, it's possible.
はぁ
Looks like they treated
you very roughly.
相当 手荒な扱いを受けたようだな
奴らのやり口は分かったろう枢木一等兵
Now you know what
they're really like, Pvt. Kururugi.
ブリタニアは腐っている
Britannia is rotten.
君が世界を変えたいなら
私の仲間になれ
If you want to change the world,
then join me!
Did you...
Is it true that you killed Prince Clovis?
君は… 本当に君がクロヴィス殿下を
殺したのか？
This is war.
これは戦争だ
敵将を討ち取るのに理由がいるか？
It's natural to kill an enemy commander.
毒ガスは？　民間人を人質に取って
And the poison gas?
And taking those civilians hostage?
交渉ごとにブラフはつきもの
結果的には誰も死んでいない
Just a bluff I used for the exchange.
As a result, nobody was killed.
結果？　そうか そういう考えで
The results? Right...
That's all that matters to you.
ふっ
私のところに来い
Join me.
The Britannia you serve
is a worthless nation.
ブリタニアはお前が仕える
価値のない国だ
そうかもしれない でもっ
Maybe that's true. However!
However, I can change it
into a worthy nation!
だから僕は価値のある国に変えるんだ
ブリタニアの中から
From within Britannia!
変える？
Change it?
間違った方法で手に入れた結果に
価値はないと思うから
Because I think the ends are just as
worthless if the means to them are wrong!
待て どこへ行く？
Wait! Where are you going?!
あと１時間で軍事法廷が始まる
My court martial begins in an hour.
Are... Are you mad?!
バッ バカか お前は！
あの法廷はお前を犯人にする為に
仕組まれている
That trial is set up
just to find you guilty!
検察官も 判事も 弁護人も
The prosecution, the judge, the defense!
それでも それがルールだ
Even so, those are the rules.
僕が行かないと イレヴンや
名誉ブリタニア人に対して弾圧が始まる
If I don't go, they'll begin oppressing
Elevens and honorary Britannians.
But you will die!
だが お前は死ぬ
構わない
I don't care.
バカだ お前は
You're being stupid!
An old friend used to tell me
all the time that I was being stupid.
昔 友達にもよく言われたよ
“このバカ”って
はっ！
僕の欠点なんだろうな
I guess it's a personal fault.
君を捕まえたいが ここでは
返り討ちだろうからね
I want to bring you in, but you'd probably
just end up killing me if I tried now.
If I'm going to die,
I want to do it for the sake of everyone.
どうせ殺されるなら
僕は みんなの為に死にたい
でも
Even so... Thank you.
ありがとう 助けてくれて
For saving me.
このバカが！
You... fool!
Yes, it seems we've gotten word
from the suspect, Kururugi.
枢木容疑者から連絡が入ったようです
ゼロが解放したとみて
いいんでしょうね？
I thought Zero broke him out of captivity.
However, now that the original charges
against him have been thrown into question,
しかし 元々の殺害容疑も根拠が
曖昧になってきましたし
it's possible Pvt. Kururugi will now
be found innocent and acquitted.
枢木一等兵
これは無罪放免の可能性が…
Thank goodness.
よかったぁ
For a legal interpretation of this,
let's turn to our commentator...
法的解釈としては どうなんでしょう？
解説の…
Sayoko?
咲世子さん？
Yukedomo kemonomichi
Walking along the animal path
行けどもけものみち 獅子よ虎よと吠え
Shishi yotorayoto hoe
Roaring with the lions and tigers
茜射す空の 彼方にまほろば
Akane sasu sora no kanata ni mahoroba
Paradise lying far across a sky dyed red
幽囚の孤獨に 彷徨う青春は
Yuushuu no kodoku ni samayou seishun wa
To a youth wandering, imprisoned in loneliness
弱さと怒りが姿無き敵ですか
Yowasato ikari ga sugata naki teki desu ka
Are weakness and hatred shapeless enemies?
父を 未だ我は
Chichi yo madaware wa
Oh father, I am still...
己を知りがたし
Onore wo shirigatashi
Learning who I am
先立つ兄らの
Sakidatsu anira no
As I pursue the backs I no longer see
見えない背中を追えば
Mienai senakawo oeba
Of the elder brothers who have gone before me
迷いの一夜に明星は誘う
Mayoi no hitoyo ni
In the night I spend lost
Myoujou wa izanau
The morning star beckons to me
Shi shite owaranu
This will not end in my death
死して終わらぬ
夢を焦がれども
Yume wo kogaredomo
I long for my dream
確かな君こそ我が命
Tashika na kimi kosowaga inochi
My faith in you sustains my life
Reppu no kouya de
In the windswept wilderness
烈風の荒野で 蝶よ花よと生き
Chou yo hanayoto iki
Living with the butterflies and flowers
とこしえの春に 咲き添うまぼろし
Tokoshie no haru ni sakisou maboroshi
Blooming together in a mirage of eternal Spring
混濁の純潔 この身は汚れても
Kondaku nojunketsu
If my purity seems muddied
Kono mi wayogoretemo
And my body seems filthy
心の錦を信じていてください
Kokoro no nishiki wo shinjiteite kudasai
Please believe in the finery within my heart
母よ けして我は
Hahayo kesshite ware wa namidawo misene domo
Oh mother, I will show no tears
涙を見せねども
Ashimoto no
They vanish like...
足下の草に露は消えもせで
Kusa ni tsuyu wa kiemosede
The dew in the grass beneath my feet
甘すぎる…
Too naive.
スザクなら分かるはずだと
思っていたのに
I was sure Suzaku would understand!
体制の内部から変えていく？
Change the system from within?
バカなっ！
その体制に取り込まれるだけだ
Impossible!
The system will just swallow him up!
取り殺されるだけだ
It'll just eat him alive!
恵みを 施しを受ける生き方なんて
俺は選ばない
I can't live my life
on the charity of others!
I can't!
もう そんな支配はいらないから
I don't want to be controlled
that way any more!